#### LEONG XIN HUI

E-mail: xhleong@gmail.com | Phone: +60129130939

Website: https://xinhui-leong.github.io/



Problem solver that aims at bridging the gap between technology through data driven and creative approaches. Believer that process improvement and innovation needs to take into account the current vitals(data), process, people and technology to identify quick wins and the longer term strategy. Experienced in the areas of project management, product management, process improvement, campaign management and data analytics.

### TECHNICAL SKILL

- Analytic Tool(s): ACL, SAS, IBM SPSS, Metabase, Clevertap, Google Analytics
- Query Language(s): SQL [Redshift, Oracle, SQLite]
- Programming Language(s): Javascript, Jquery, Ruby, Python, R

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Product Team, IKEA SEA & Mexico – Product Manager, Digital Solutions (Contract)

November 2020 – Current

- > Responsible for digital solution sourcing to implementation within IKEA SEA & Mexico
- > Work with key stakeholders to determine requirements and solution required within the store and develop product roadmap and backlog
- > Work with interdepartmental teams for implementation of solution and perform training for key superusers

### Data Science Certification Course, 360DigiTMG – Coursework

February 2020 – June 2020

➤ Work with coursemates remotely on data assignments and projects

### **Growth Team, HealthifyMe** – Associate Product Manager

June 2019 – December 2019

- > Responsible for reviewing and driving growth for Malaysia and Singapore through the HealthifyMe app
- > Obtained feedback from users on key features and challenges faced to design new features/enhancements
- > Work with tech and design team to develop product features (UI/UX) based on defined user stories
- > Developed test plan for positive and negative scenarios and perform user testing prior to launch of product features
- ➤ Developed dashboard to track key business metrics and performance of features

# **Transformation Team, U Mobile** – Assistant Manager/Product Owner(App)

November 2018 – June 2019

- Responsible for new app development and the development of digital roadmap for unification of app and platforms
- > Work with key stakeholders to setup project workflow and adoption of SCRUM for mobile app development
- > Identified key business objectives for new app development and determine key stakeholders to be involved
- > Host workshops with key stakeholders to identify key business requirements and to align requirements to develop long term app roadmap and developed user stories
- > Defined key metrics and perform analytics using SAS, SOL Queries and IBM SPSS to identify and track historical metrics and develop reports and tracker of current app performance as basis for the new app
- Developed product backlog based on the following prioritisation:
  - Criticality of feature to business based on user feedback and cost/revenue impact
  - Data driven analysis of current app usage to determine revenue and usage impact
  - Key metrics and data field requirements to track revenue, engagement and customer behaviour

## Mentoring & Engineering Team, NEXT Academy – Mentor/Junior Engineer

April 2018 – November 2018

- Review course materials and work with mentor team to restructure course delivery and syllabus for effective learning. Key objective was to engage students and to train students to be self sufficient
- ➤ Mentored students on the following tech stack:
  - Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap
  - Backend: Ruby on Rails, SQL

## Campaign Management System Implementation - Campaign Team/Product Owner

- ➤ Define business requirement and structure of campaign system through incorporating user and customer experience. Structure takes into consideration business objectives, customer experience, inter department user experience and feedback loop for campaign recalibration
- > Identify key business objectives and perform campaign planning to define data frequency and data fields required for performance monitoring, customer segmentation and behavioral analysis
- ➤ Work closely with IT Project Manager and Vendors in ensuring requirements are met and identify workaround solutions where technical solutions are unable to meet business requirements
- Review test plan to ensure completeness of positive and negative scenarios based on business requirements. Perform UAT and post deployment live test prior to official launch

## Acquisition, Upgrade and Loyalty Campaign – Campaign Team/Product Owner

- ➤ Identified key metrics based on business objective and developed report structure for high level monitoring and management reporting
- > Perform analytics using SAS queries and IBM SPSS on industry trends, customer segment and align findings with key business objective to identify campaign opportunities
- ➤ Plan and map the end-to-end customer journey whilst considering currently available resources, enhancements or process changes. For enhancement and campaign execution, considered both timeline and cost impact.
- > Define business requirements and platform requirements where applicable for campaign execution. Review test plan and perform UAT and post deployment live test prior to launch
- Engage and work with cross-functional teams critical for execution of campaign

# **Enterprise Risk Services, Deloitte** – Senior Consultant

November 2011 – October 2015

## Selected Project Highlights:

# GST Project Management Office (Insurance Industry) – Team Lead

- ➤ Review the impact of GST to clients' environment through understanding clients' current business process and system functional aspects
- ➤ Enhance and develop new system and process workflows to incorporate GST requirements throughout clients' operations including the following:
  - Studying and understanding the impact of GST to the insurance industry
  - Understanding of clients' current business process and the existing IT systems' design and functional aspects
  - Leading and conducting GST workshop with the various division to share and obtain consensus for technical and business solutioning
  - Developing the GST Standard Operating Procedures for all divisions impacted by GST
- Monitor project progress and ensuring pre-set project timelines are met
- > Perform data verification for validity of data crucial to GST computation
- > Perform recomputation to ensure accuracy of system computation and output based on the GST requirement

## ERP System Evaluation and Review (Water Services Industry) - Team Lead

- > Evaluated and identified areas for system enhancement in clients' existing ERP system through:
  - Identifying gaps in current ERP system and current business processes
  - Determining the risk and impact of existing gaps
  - Prioritising enhancement listing based on the impact to client and estimating the effort required
- > Conducted workshops to identify areas for enhancements and presented recommendations to management

### Revenue Recognition Review (Online Payment Industry) - Team Lead

- Assisted client with the identification of revenue and deferred revenue through:
  - Understanding clients' existing products, business channels and accounting standards impacting revenue recognition
  - Understanding the clients' IT systems and accounting practices to identify data extraction points
  - Performed analytics with ACL scripting to quantify year-end, deferred revenue and provisions

### **EDUCATION**

Data Science Certification Course – 360DigiTMG, Malaysia

February 2020 – June 2020

Full Stack Web Development Quantum Degree – NEXT Academy, Malaysia

January 2018 – March 2018

**Bachelor of Commerce** – *University of Victoria, Canada* 

September 2009 – August 2011

American Degree Program – Taylor's University College, Malaysia

January 2007 – August 2008